<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<KTouchLecture>
 <Title>English (EASY)</Title>
 <Comment>KTouch training file generated Sun Mar 11 09:59:58 2007
Perl Script written by Steinar Theigmann and Håvard Frøiland.
Re-written for Kortepohja elementary school in Jyväskylä, Finland, in October 2013 by Terho Reuhkala.</Comment>
 <FontSuggestions>Monospace</FontSuggestions>
 <Levels>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>jf</NewCharacters>
   <Line>fj j f j f f fj f fj fj ffj f fjf f f jj f fj jf jf fj jfj fjf</Line>
   <Line>ffj ffj fj ff f f ff fj fj ffjj jjjf j f jj fj jj jfj ff f ff ff</Line>
   <Line>fj ffj ff jfj jf jff ffj f ff ffj f fjf j fj ffj fj jj ffj jj f</Line>
   <Line>jfj jff j ffj ffjj ff j f fjf ffj jff ffj jf ffj jff fj fj f f f</Line>
   <Line>f fj jff ffj fjf f j j jf jf j jfj fjf fj ff fj jfj jfj fj jff</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>kd</NewCharacters>
   <Line>kk dd kk dd kd kd dk dk kd kd dk dk dkkd ddkk kkdd ddkk kkdd ddkk kddk</Line>
   <Line>dfj djd fkkk fk dff d dkkf fd fk fdfj fk k dkkf djd dff dkd dff</Line>
   <Line>dkd kdk k dkkf k jk fkkk jd k jfkd fk fk jd k d dkd jd k dd kd dffd</Line>
   <Line>d fk k k dff dff dd fk fk fd jd dd jjd kd dkd dkf kdk fdfj d kdk</Line>
   <Line>djd k fk kd dd fk dff dff kdk dkd dkf d k jk jfkd jd jfkd d kdk</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>ls</NewCharacters>
   <Line>ll ss ll ss sl sl ls ls sl sl ls ls slls ssll llss ssll llss ssll lssl</Line>
   <Line>l slj jl lkj l ldf s ld ll l ll ldk jjdl dlkk fl ls dss fld fl</Line>
   <Line>kl fl fl lkj fld ld fld js l dss kl jl jl ldk fld s ls s js kl</Line>
   <Line>ll ld dss fld l ls sf dss ll jl kl ls slj kl ldf kl dss ls ls js</Line>
   <Line>s dlkk js kl js ls fld jl jjdl ll jjdl ll ls ldf ls ld ldk slj</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>a</NewCharacters>
   <Line>a aa a aa af af aj aj af af aj aj aja jaja lala dada fafa aaaa</Line>
   <Line>ask flask ask flask ask flask dad salad dad salad dad salad</Line>
   <Line>alaska lass dallas lad sad ads lad falls lass falls sad ads</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>c</NewCharacters>
   <Line>c cc cccc ca ca cs cs cl cl ck ck casa ckck fcfc ckck fcfc lclc kckc</Line>
   <Line>all call all call all call class fall class fall class jack dallas</Line>
   <Line>jack alaska jack alaska dallas lack dallas lack ask jack ask jack</Line>
   <Line>scald jackal scald jackal lack class lack class cd jack cd jack</Line>	 
   <Line>jackal flask jackal flask alaska sack alaska sack fall class fall class</Line>
   <Line>slack all class slack all class lack scald lack scald jack lacks class</Line>
   <Line>ack dad ack dad scald dallas scald dallas sack flask sack flask</Line>
   <Line>salad call flask as all sass dad class alaska dallas scald lack</Line>
   <Line>salsa fall dad salad casa sack jack lack ask flask a clad jackal</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>nt</NewCharacters>
   <Line>dan and alan dan and alan land sand land sand dan and alan dan and alan</Line>
   <Line>flat tall flat tall cat talk cat talk flat tall flat tall</Line>
   <Line>an attack an attack fast snack fast snack last stand last stand</Line>
   <Line>sand ant sand ant kansas sank kansas sank tall stand stands tall</Line>
   <Line>flat land flatland fact sand fact sand can stand can stand</Line>
   <Line>fan dan an attack alan fast snack tank and land stand fast snack</Line>
   <Line>tan ant flat land flatland can fact stand tnt tall santa cat</Line>
   <Line>snacks attacks fact flatlands talk task fan tan can fat</Line>
   <Line>task cast tan kansas sank tall sandals canada fans jack lacks tact</Line>
   <Line>tank fact scandal landfall talk and land sand salt fan tank tan</Line>
   <Line>scandal flank last task snack santa kansas canada fat flatland</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>iv</NewCharacters>
   <Line>i ii iii iv v vi vii viii villain vanilla villain vanilla villain vanilla</Line>
   <Line>vain diva vain diva ink in a vial ink in a vial vain diva vain diva</Line>		
   <Line>vivid tint vivid tint valiant david valiant david visit latvia</Line>
   <Line>visit latvia skin vain skin vain final villain final villain</Line>
   <Line>david visits latvia david visits latvia final stain final stain</Line>
   <Line>vanilla anvil villain latvia david vial ink stain valiant skin</Line>
   <Line>distant final visit vain diva vanilla fantastic fit kill insist</Line>
   <Line>satin latin vast saint villain latvia tick tack distant skin</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>me</NewCharacters>
   <Line>me me same me meet me meet me mate met me mate met me fame same name same</Line>
   <Line>lame tame came fame same name lame tame came fame same name flame</Line>
   <Line>make made make made smile smell smile smell sesame vitamine</Line>
   <Line>same time same name same time same name vitamine sesame flame</Line>
   <Line>make mess made mess male female male female vitamine sesame</Line>
   <Line>smell smelled smell smelled tame camel tame camel milk meal</Line>
   <Line>vitamine milk sesame meal flame time same name smile smell mess</Line>
   <Line>me fame me same flame same fame make mess made mess flame same fame</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>hr</NewCharacters>
   <Line>hard hair hard hair hard hair hard hair sahara shark sahara shark sahara shark</Line>
   <Line>sarah herself sarah herself shark hair hard sahara shark hair hard sahara</Line>
   <Line>shirt shiver shirt shiver here are the hammers here are the hammers</Line>
   <Line>rehearse this rehearse this fresh fish fresh fish rich french father</Line>
   <Line>rich french father rehearse this shiver french fish rich sarah herself</Line>
   <Line>fisher shark fisher shark thirteen shirts thirteen shirts rehearse this</Line>
   <Line>hard shiver hair shark hammer sarah father thirteen rich herself french</Line>
   <Line>chair feather earth threat share theatre hire hear stretch slither starfish</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>go</NewCharacters>
   <Line>dog fog go goal god gold golf good jog log logo flog dog gold golf</Line>
   <Line>go go good dog go go good dog gold golf gold golf go go good dog</Line>
   <Line>good gloves good gloves strong gorilla strong gorilla dog golf gold</Line>
   <Line>great dragon great dragon among alligators among alligators</Line>
   <Line>forgiving flamingo forgiving flamingo long dragon long dragon</Line>
   <Line>great song good song forget forgive forget forgive gorilla golf gold</Line>
   <Line>among dragons among alligators golden dog golden dragon good golfer</Line>
   <Line>cooking together cooking together strong george among alligators</Line>
   <Line>jog gloves comic smoking forget clothing cottage gasoline longing lagoon</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>bp</NewCharacters>
   <Line>bad pie bad pie bed pen bed pen bad pie bad pie point bike point bike</Line>
   <Line>big paper big paper bad pie big bike important point important point</Line>
   <Line>brave people bad pepper brave people bad pepper brave people bad pepper</Line>
   <Line>blood problem blood problem important people rabbit table rabbit table</Line>
   <Line>problem rabbit table people brave bird pepper potato table important</Line>
   <Line>problem people brave bird potato table pepper rabbit blood dolphin</Line>
   <Line>pie paper bed table pepper potato rabbit blood bird brave bad bike</Line>
   <Line>big ben horrible sibling sailboat pocket pick berries vegetable</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>qu</NewCharacters>
   <Line>quiet quick full sauna quiet quick full sauna quiet quick sun mum sun mum</Line>
   <Line>quite quiet queen quite quiet queen usual request usual request quick mum</Line>
   <Line>question full sauna question request sun quote mum quote mum quarter</Line>
   <Line>request quarter request quarter adult squirrel adult squirrel quote quarter</Line>
   <Line>quit quiver quit quiver queue request queue request aqua aquarium aqua aquarium</Line>
   <Line>mosquito fault mosquito fault aquarium quarter aquarium quarter fault request</Line>
   <Line>trust bouquet fault mosquito equal adult mosquito trust quiver quote quiet</Line>
   <Line>full sauna full aquarium liquid aqua liquid aqua quit request quit quirk</Line>
   <Line>conquer equip antique aquatic double triple quadruple quintuple acquire equator</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>w</NewCharacters>
   <Line>jaw law saw jaw law saw walk wall walk wall jaw law saw jaw law saw walk wall</Line>
   <Line>quiet wind wait wind wait quiet swim wild swim wild mosquito wall windmill</Line>
   <Line>quick twist walk wait quick twist walk wait swim windmill quit law lawn</Line>
   <Line>wild swan wild swan queue wife kiwi wife kiwi twist wrist twist wrist quarter</Line>
   <Line>news war news war want pillow request pillow blow wise wasp sparrow</Line>
   <Line>owner homework owner homework water down water down swap wallpaper</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>x</NewCharacters>
   <Line>ix x xi xii xiii xiv xv xvi xvii taxi fox taxi fox</Line>
   <Line>six sex six sex mix box mix box exit text exit text</Line>
   <Line>explain alexander explain alexander boxer flex boxer flex</Line>
   <Line>explode box explode box except accept except accept</Line>
   <Line>extreme refkex saxophone toxic sphinx</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>yz</NewCharacters>
   <Line>yummy pizza yummy pizza lazy lady cozy mystery lazy lady cozy mystery</Line>
   <Line>hazy sky hazy sky amazing zebra amazing zebra yellow way yellow way</Line>
   <Line>why nowadays why nowadays xylitol worry xylitol worry squeeze</Line>
   <Line>sixty cowboys squeeze sixty cowboys drowsy rhythm drowsy rhythm</Line>
   <Line>snowy day snowy yard zip unzip mozzarella xylophone</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ</NewCharacters>
   <Line>Adam Barbara Cecilia David England Finland Gabriel Helsinki Ireland</Line>
   <Line>John Katarina Laura Marcus Nils Oslo Peru Quentin Rudolph Stanley</Line>
   <Line>Turkey USA Venice Xavier Yasmina Zimbabwe</Line>
   <Line>Alan Beijing Charles Desiree Ethan Fiona Gibraltar Hank I Jersey</Line>
   <Line>Kortepohja London Massachusetts Niagara Olive Paul Qatar Reykjavik</Line>
   <Line>Stockholm Travis Uppsala Valentine Xiamen Yokohama Zorro</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>. , ' ! ?</NewCharacters>
   <Line>, , , . . . ' ' ' ! ! ! ? ? ? '' ' ' ,, .,., !?</Line>
   <Line>I can't type. He wouldn't know. Do you? It's a fine day today, isn't it?</Line>
   <Line>Alas! It was dark. It was rainy. Alan couldn't see far ahead.</Line>
   <Line>You need a pencil, an eraser, paper, glue and scissors.</Line>
   <Line>Jack, who wasn't even invited, was there. The girls' dresses, the boys' suits.</Line>
  </Level>
 </Levels>
</KTouchLecture>
