<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<KTouchLecture>
 <Title>English (DIFFICULT)</Title>
 <Comment>KTouch training file generated Sun Mar 11 09:59:58 2007
Perl Script written by Steinar Theigmann and Håvard Frøiland.
Re-written for Kortepohja elementary school in Jyväskylä, Finland, in October 2013 by Terho Reuhkala.</Comment>
 <FontSuggestions>Monospace</FontSuggestions>
 <Levels>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>jf</NewCharacters>
   <Line>fj j f j f f fj f fj fj ffj f fjf f f jj f fj jf jf fj jfj fjf</Line>
   <Line>ffj ffj fj ff f f ff fj fj ffjj jjjf j f jj fj jj jfj ff f ff ff</Line>
   <Line>fj ffj ff jfj jf jff ffj f ff ffj f fjf j fj ffj fj jj ffj jj f</Line>
   <Line>jfj jff j ffj ffjj ff j f fjf ffj jff ffj jf ffj jff fj fj f f f</Line>
   <Line>f fj jff ffj fjf f j j jf jf j jfj fjf fj ff fj jfj jfj fj jff</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>kd</NewCharacters>
   <Line>kk dd kk dd kd kd dk dk kd kd dk dk dkkd ddkk kkdd ddkk kkdd ddkk kddk</Line>
   <Line>dfj djd fkkk fk dff d dkkf fd fk fdfj fk k dkkf djd dff dkd dff</Line>
   <Line>dkd kdk k dkkf k jk fkkk jd k jfkd fk fk jd k d dkd jd k dd kd dffd</Line>
   <Line>d fk k k dff dff dd fk fk fd jd dd jjd kd dkd dkf kdk fdfj d kdk</Line>
   <Line>djd k fk kd dd fk dff dff kdk dkd dkf d k jk jfkd jd jfkd d kdk</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>ls</NewCharacters>
   <Line>ll ss ll ss sl sl ls ls sl sl ls ls slls ssll llss ssll llss ssll lssl</Line>
   <Line>l slj jl lkj l ldf s ld ll l ll ldk jjdl dlkk fl ls dss fld fl</Line>
   <Line>kl fl fl lkj fld ld fld js l dss kl jl jl ldk fld s ls s js kl</Line>
   <Line>ll ld dss fld l ls sf dss ll jl kl ls slj kl ldf kl dss ls ls js</Line>
   <Line>s dlkk js kl js ls fld jl jjdl ll jjdl ll ls ldf ls ld ldk slj</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>a</NewCharacters>
   <Line>a aa a aa af af aj aj af af aj aj aja jaja lala dada fafa lala</Line>
   <Line>ask flask ask flask ask flask dad salad dad salad dad salad</Line>
   <Line>alaska lass dallas lad sad ads lad falls lass falls sad ads</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>c</NewCharacters>
   <Line>c cc cccc ca ca cs cs cl cl ck ck casa ckck fcfc ckck fcfc lclc kckc</Line>
   <Line>all call all call all call class class class jack jack jack</Line>
   <Line>scald jackal scald jackal lack class lack class cd jack cd jack</Line>	 
   <Line>jack alack jack alack clad scald clad scald class lack class lack</Line>
   <Line>slack clad slack clad scald dad scald dad alack jack lacks class</Line>
   <Line>ack dad ack dad scald dallas scald dallas sack flask sack flask</Line>
   <Line>salad call scald flask as all sass dad class alaska dallas</Line>
   <Line>fall dad alack salad casa sack jack lack ask flask a clad jackal</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>nt</NewCharacters>
   <Line>fan dan an attack alan scant fast snack tank scandal and land</Line>
   <Line>tan tact ant flat land flatland can fact stand tnt</Line>
   <Line>tall santa slant snacks attack cast fact flatlands cat stank</Line>
   <Line>tad stalk task cast tan nasal kansas sank tall sandals canada</Line>
   <Line>flank tank lank fact scandal landfall clan talk talc sancta</Line>
   <Line>fans stall knack and land sand salt canasta jack lacks tact</Line>
   <Line>scandal flank last stat slant task snack santa kansas canada</Line>
   <Line>nasa fat flatland scant clank staff fan talk cast task</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>iv</NewCharacters>
   <Line>i ii iii iv v vi vii viii villain vanilla david visits latvia</Line>
   <Line>anvil divan a vain diva a valiant civilian a scandinavian activist</Line>
   <Line>vatican vivid vial vital avail livid avian vandalistic ant saint fanatic</Line>
   <Line>assistant stain satin install intact distant cassis sick tint flint</Line>
   <Line>titanic infant insist ink kin skin latin instant initial inflict</Line>
   <Line>fantastic standstill tactic final finalist kill clinical fit</Line>
   <Line>assail distill flick lilac tick tack canvas instinct illicit</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>me</NewCharacters>
   <Line>me fame me same flame same fame make mess made mess flame same fame</Line>
   <Line>smell smelled melt smelt smelted slim smile vitamine mend make amends</Line>
   <Line>elm male female medal meddle salesman seems nice seam seamless sesame</Line>
   <Line>meet camel cement element madness demean calmness clam lament statement</Line>
   <Line>dividend caveman dave leave evade canvas vent medieval vietnamese vase</Line>
   <Line>name tame team tandem mess menace esteem mental testament mean edam</Line>
   <Line>vie fee descent fiesta title site select fifties seventeen skillet teatime</Line>
   <Line>slate filmed lacked mate entitlement stale accidental seek steak skimmed</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>hr</NewCharacters>
   <Line>sarah sahara shark shard sarah sahara shark shard harass hard rash</Line>
   <Line>fisher hear herself hare hair heir hire refresh rehearse shear sheer</Line>
   <Line>shaker shrill shriek shirk shred radish sheriff share hear heard herd herded</Line>
   <Line>adhere theatre thinker threat thirteen shirt shelter slither stretch</Line>
   <Line>starfish silversmith shelf shimmer rich reach heartless headmaster</Line>
   <Line>hinder harvest hammer french father feather earth either diarrhea</Line>
   <Line>chair charles cheddar charm cathedral cashier archer architect archive</Line>
   <Line>cheater cheer children christian heart trash stretch third thirst thrive</Line>
   <Line>varnish verandah thick thanks stitch scratch shine search shatter richard</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>go</NewCharacters>
   <Line>dog fog go goal god gold golf good jog log logo flog dog gold golf</Line>
   <Line>hog galosh goldfish dialog igloo gloom dodge gloss goggles goose hedgehog</Line>
   <Line>lodge ogle goalie goldfish geologist jogger gorilla gross gloves george</Line>
   <Line>song strong great stage average age john million look noon onion join honk</Line>
   <Line>tonight together foreign among alligators forgiven forgotten congestion</Line>
   <Line>clothing cooking cog cottage doings dragon frog maggot altogether</Line>
   <Line>grave regret lifelong logic mango orange an astonishing archaeologist</Line>
   <Line>go gone golden lagoon long longing gasoline smoking flamingo among</Line>
   <Line>foliage gasoline ghost glove goat ignore kilogram foreleg engross</Line>
   <Line>overcook rotate comic gentle clock collide glister favor solstice</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>bp</NewCharacters>
   <Line>blood problem blood problem important people rabbit table bird potato</Line>
   <Line>problem rabbit table people brave bird pepper potato table important problem</Line>
   <Line>problem people brave bird potato table pepper rabbit blood problem dolphin</Line>
   <Line>pie paper bed table pepper potato rabbit blood bird brave bad bike</Line>
   <Line>big ben horrible sibling sailboat pocket pick berries vegetable</Line>
   <Line>parent parliament dabble oppose grab boast horrible brittle dolphin</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>qu</NewCharacters>
   <Line>quite quiet question full sauna quiet request full sun quote mum quote mum quarter</Line>
   <Line>request quarter quite quiet queen quote quirk quiet queen question full sauna</Line>
   <Line>quit quiver quit quiver quote request quote request aqua aquarium aqua aquarium</Line>
   <Line>trust bouquet fault mosquito equal adult request quiver aqua quote quiet</Line>
   <Line>full sauna full aquarium liquid aqua liquid aqua quit request quit quirk</Line>
   <Line>quick quiet bouquet equal liquid mosquito qualm bouquet quiver quaint quirk</Line>
   <Line>aquatic antique conquer technique squeak acquire squish turquoise squirm</Line>
   <Line>vanquish technique unrequited love squat squeaking squirrel queue quarrel</Line>
   <Line>equip double triple quadruple quintuple acquire equator qualified ventriloquist</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>w</NewCharacters>
   <Line>twist walk wait twist walk wait swim windmill lawn jaw law lawn wall wind</Line>
   <Line>want swamp quit want swamp queue will weep request will weep squirrel</Line>
   <Line>sweep wipe quarrel sweep wipe quarrel snow quiet wrinkle snow quiet wrinkle</Line>
   <Line>down work queen power view mosquito town water bouquet willpower question</Line>
   <Line>sparrow worm twist wrist view town wallpaper wine wasp windowpane</Line>
   <Line>cow pillow equal wrap wilt swamp squirrel sweep wipe water down swap homework</Line>
   <Line>quiet walrus where wake weave wise squeak would view crossword blow wheat awful</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>x</NewCharacters>
   <Line>ix x xi xii xiii xiv xv xvi xvii taxi fox ox fix</Line>
   <Line>six sex mix flex tax wax ax box exit text hoax vex</Line>
   <Line>exist extreme extract expand exhale reflex saxophone</Line>
   <Line>sphinx suffix toxic obnoxious explode expire exploit explain</Line>
   <Line>explore expose expert alexander apex boxer accept except</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>yz</NewCharacters>
   <Line>yummy pizza lazy lady cozy mystery lazy lady cozy mystery</Line>
   <Line>hazy sky hazy sky amazing yellow zebra snowy way snowy yard</Line>
   <Line>why nowadays sleazy cowboy lizard pizza zip unzip blizzard</Line>
   <Line>sixty rhythm puzzle maze drowsy rhythm xylitol worry haywire</Line>
   <Line>sneeze frenzy razor jazz xylophone quizzical squeeze sly lawyer</Line>
   <Line>size seize zoo ooze ozone zone zombie xylophone awry muzzle mozzarella yard rhyme rye wry</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ</NewCharacters>
   <Line>Adam Barbara Cecilia David England Finland Gabriel Helsinki Ireland</Line>
   <Line>John Katarina Laura Marcus Nils Oslo Peru Quentin Rudolph Stanley</Line>
   <Line>Turkey USA Venice Xavier Yasmina Zimbabwe</Line>
   <Line>Alan Beijing Charles Desiree Ethan Fiona Gibraltar Hank I Jersey</Line>
   <Line>Kortepohja London Massachusetts Niagara Olive Paul Qatar Reykjavik</Line>
   <Line>Stockholm Travis Uppsala Valentine Xiamen Yokohama Zorro</Line>
  </Level>
  <Level>
   <NewCharacters>. , ' ! ?</NewCharacters>
   <Line>, , , . . . ' ' ' ! ! ! ? ? ? '' ' ' ,, .,., !?</Line>
   <Line>I can't type. He wouldn't know. Do you? It's a fine day today, isn't it?</Line>
   <Line>Alas! It was dark. It was rainy. Alan couldn't see far ahead.</Line>
   <Line>You need a pencil, an eraser, paper, glue and scissors.</Line>
   <Line>Jack, who wasn't even invited, was there. The girls' dresses, the boys' suits.</Line>
  </Level>
 </Levels>
</KTouchLecture>
